# Georgios Vavouliotis | Curriculum Vitae

Travessera de Les Corts 37, 08028 - Barcelona - Spain

☑ gvavou5@gmail.com • ② gvavou5.github.io • in georgios-vavouliotis

### **Profile**

I earned my diploma on Electrical and Computer Engineering from the National Technical University of Athens (NTUA). Currently, I am a 3rd year Ph.D. student in Computer Science at Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC) and Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS). My supervisors are Dr. Marc Casas Guix from BSC-CNS and Dr. Lluc Alvarez from UPC. Moreover, I collaborate with Prof. Daniel A. Jiménez from Texas A&M University and Prof. Boris Grot from the University of Edinburgh. My research aims at designing intelligent microarchitectural prediction/prefetching mechanisms for the cache and the TLB hierarchy.

# Areas of (Research) Interest

Computer Architecture, High Performance Computing (HPC) Systems, Machine Learning for Computer Architecture; identifying and exploiting the predictability of programs to design microarchitectural prefetching/prediction mechanisms for the cache and the TLB hierarchy, improving the cache/TLB management, and leveraging machine learning algorithms to design intelligent microarchitectural components.

### **Education**

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC)

Barcelona

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.)

Leveraging Artificial Intelligence Algorithms for Hardware Prediction

September 2018-now

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

Oiploma on Electrical & Computer Engineering, 300 ECTS, GPA: 8.9/10

2012-March 2018

Academic Directions.....

- Computer Systems & Software
- Computer Networks and Networks Security
- Signal Processing, Automatic Control and Robotics

Diploma Thesis

Performance Analysis of TLB Prefetching Mechanisms, GPA: 10/10

General Lyceum, Chalkida, Greece

Chalkida

Apolytirion, Top 0.2% in National Qualification Exams, GPA: 19.5/20

2009-2012

# Research Experience

### **Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)**

Barcelona

Researcher at Computer Architecture & Operating Systems Group (CAOS) September 2018-now

### National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

Research Student at Computer Systems Laboratory (CSLab)

February 2018-July 2018

## **Participation in Projects**

### SOW 5.3 - Intel and BSC-CNS Collaboration

Barcelona

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

September 2018-now

High Performance Computing VII

Barcelona

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

September 2018-now

### **Publications**

- [1] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Boris Grot, Daniel A. Jiménez, Marc Casas Guix, *Morrigan:* **A Composite Instruction TLB Prefetcher**. Proceedings of the 54th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO), Virtual, October 2021.
- [1] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Vasileios Karakostas, Konstantinos Nikas, Nectarios Koziris, Daniel A. Jiménez, Marc Casas Guix, *Exploiting Page Table Locality for Agile TLB Prefetching*. Proceedings of the 48th International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA), Virtual, June 2021.
- [2] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Daniel A. Jiménez, Marc Casas Guix, *Cost-Effective Instruction TLB Prefetching*. Second Young Architect Workshop (YArch 2020). In conjunction with The 25th ACM International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems (ASPLOS), Virtual, March 2020.
- [3] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Goumas Georgios, "Performance Analysis of TLB Prefetching Mechanisms". Book of my diploma thesis.

### **Technical Reviewer for Conferences**

18th ACM International Conference on Computing Frontiers (CF'21)

Sub-reviewer

**IEEE Supercomputing Conference (SC'21)** 

Sub-reviewer

# **Teaching Experience**

Private Tutor Athens

During my Diploma I was giving private lectures to:

2013-2018

**Undergraduate students of Computer Science Department** 

C programming, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, Automatic Control

### High school students

Mathematics, Physics

# Lab Assistant at National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

**Athens** 

C programming

2013-2017

# **Seminars and Training Courses**

### **Summer Schools**

Participation in accredited Summer Schools (certification provided)

### HPC Architectures for Artificial Intelligence and Dedicated Applications

Provided by ACM-Europe, 30 - 3 August 2021

### **HPC Architectures for Artificial Intelligence and Dedicated Applications**

Provided by ACM-Europe, 17 - 24 July 2019

Participation in accredited seminars (certification provided)

### Introduction to Big Data & Practical Data Analytics for Solving Real World Problems

Provided by PACT BSC-CNS, February 2021

### Introduction to Heterogenous Memory Usage

Provided by PACT BSC-CNS, February 2019

### **Online Courses (MOOCs)**

Courses offered by accredited universities and training programs (certification provided)

### **Machine Learning**

Provided by Stanford University (Prof. Andrew Ng), May 2018 - July 2018, GPA: 10/10

- · Supervised Learning (Regression Models, SVMs, NN)
- · Unsupervised Learning (Clustering, Dimensionality Reduction)

### **Advanced Programming with Python**

Provided by Mathesis Online Platform, March 2018 - April 2018, GPA: 10/10

- · Object Oriented Programming
- · Data Storage (sqlite3, pickle, JSON)
- · Graphic Interface Programming and Game Development

### **Technical and Personal skills**

### Programming Languages:

- Advanced knowledge: C

- Working knowledge: C++, Python, Matlab, Assembly (8085, 8086, AVR), SML/NJ, HTML

### o Tools:

- Advanced knowledge: Unix Bash, LATEX, SVN

- Working knowledge: Git, CACTI, MS Office

### o Simulators:

- Advanced knowledge: ChampSim

### General Business Skills:

- Ability to work with a team

- Very good presentation skills
- Able to write well organized and structured reports

### **Honors and Awards**

0	2019 FPI Doctoral Fellowship Funded by Spanish Government (MINECO)	<b>Barcelona</b> 2019-2022
0	Mathematics Award - National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)  Excellent marks in all mathematical courses during the first two (2) years.	<b>Athens</b> 2014
0	"The Great Moment of Education" Eurobank EFG Scholarship Highest rank in National Qualifications Exams in my school	Chalkida 2012

### **Affiliations**

o Affiliated PhD student in HiPEAC (European Network of Excellence on High Performance and Embedded Arcitecture and Compilation)

# Languages

Greek (Native)English (B2 (FCE, KPG))Italian (Beginner)Spanish (Beginner)

# Personal Interests and extra-curricular activity

CookingChallengesBasketballWritingCinema

### References

References available upon request.